NIGEL MARSHAL

FRONT-END ENGINEER

ABOUT

Possess six years of front-end development experience along with project & technical management experience; managing outsourced international development teams and handling client requests. Most recently worked as a front-end developer for ADDA creating multiple government entity Sitecore websites and building modular website components. Strong core in UX, having taken the HFI UX course and worked in one of the top MENA UX digital agencies as a UX Specialist / UX Developer. Experience in key technologies and tools such as React.js, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, ECMAScript (ES6, ES7 JavaScript) and Git, to build & deliver robust SPAs and websites. Actively learning to stay ahead of the curve.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



FRONT-END CONSULTANT (CONTRACT) / DEVELOPER

Abu Dhabi Digital Authority (ADDA) | December 2019 - March 2021

- Developed 10+ government entity Sitecore websites for the Abu Dhabi Government TAMM Project whilst being a member of multiple development SCRUM teams.
- Built custom HTML and JavaScript modular components for teams to integrate in subsites, that were customizable with SASS variables to follow branding themes.
- Created and maintained documentation for developed components and subsites to contribute to the development wiki accessed by 10+ teams on Confluence.

dubizzle FRONT-END ENGINEER

dubizzle | January 2019 - November 2019

- Oversaw frontend development as the sole front-end support for OLX MENA, spanning 8 countries including Lebanon, Egypt and Oman.
- Led the front-end initiative to implement new paid product features for OLX MENA, to generate passive revenue for the company and boost users ad reach by
- · Worked as an integral instructor on a code migration initiative, guiding 5 international colleagues in helping them move from a custom PHP framework codebase to React as well as assist with RTL migration issues.
- Maintained, optimized and converted outdated custom PHP MVC front-end code to more robust future-proof code using React and third party libraries.
- Compiled documentation & wikis for on-boarding new developers on key projects.

thi UX SPECIALIST & UX DEVELOPER

rbbi | September 2015 - March 2018

- Built fully responsive and comprehensive websites using HTML5 and SCSS with a user-centered approach as part of the core development team.
- Supervised outsourced development teams of 8+ members as a hybrid Technical/Project manager for client deliverables and code collaboration.
- Managed client-facing communications with regards to project progress, change requests and trouble shooting while spearheading development progress for 3 large website projects including Banking and Real estate.
- Coordinated with cross departments including SEO, Analytics, CRO (A/B Testing) and Content teams for websites ranging from landing pages, WordPress sites, web apps and e-commerce.
- Accomplished closing one of the longest running projects for the company after taking over and leading as a project manager on an emergency basis.

CONTACT

in linkedin.com/in/nigelmarshal

nigelmarshal.com

github.com/NigelMarshal

+971563982449

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (WITH DISTINCTION): **COMPUTER SYSTEMS**

2012 - 2015

Heriot-Watt University -School of Mathematical and Computer Sciences, Dubai, UAE

CODING

React

TypeScript

JavaScript

SCSS (BEM Methodology)

CSS Flex

HTMI 5

Responsive Design

RESTful APIs

PHP

webpack

npm

gulp

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Scrum Agile Methodologies JIRA

Confluence

Trello

DESIGN

Sketch

Adobe Photoshop

Figma

Axure

LANGUAGES

English (Native) Hindi (Intermediate) Urdu (Intermediate)

Malayalam (Intermediate)